妈妈
Mom.
妈  你在吗
Mom, are you here?
不要啊
Come on.
快点  妈妈  接电话
Come on, mom. Answer.
你们好
Oh, hello.
你不是应该上学去了吗
Shouldn't you be in school already?
还有一个小时才上课呢
School doesn't start for another hour.
是啊  如果你出去过夜
Yeah. If you were hoping to do
想一个人偷偷溜回来
the walk of shame in private,
真是不走运
You're outta luck.
别犯傻
Oh, don't be silly.
我只是没想到时间还早
I just didn't realize how early it was.
我被其他的东西搞得心神不宁
I have been a bit distracted this morning.
心神不宁
Do you mean distracted,
还是你被手指上这枚超大的钻戒
or hypnotized by that giant rock
闪晕了
on your finger?!
天啊  切特·帕拉本求婚了
Wow. Did Chet Palaburn propose?
阿丽克西斯  我想我们要管他叫
Uh, Alexis, I think it's about time we start
切特叔叔才比较得体
calling him Uncle Chet.
等等  你们两个等一下
Oh, now wait a minute. Wait a minute, you two.
我没订婚  好吧
I am not engaged, all right?
没错  切特昨晚的确求婚了
Yes, Chet did propose last night
我告诉他我需要考虑考虑
and I told him, you know, I needed time to think about it,
他坚持让我
And he insisted I keep
在考虑的时候留着戒指
the ring while I make up my mind, so...
真是个聪明的男人
Mm. Smart man. Mm.
钻石很有说服力的
Diamonds can be very persuasive.
我都听得到它的低吟"留下我  留下我"
I can hear it now, whispering... "Keep me. Keep me."
坏消息是  用"道上的说法"
Unfortunately, now that Chet has upped the ante,
现在切特提高了赌注  我要决定
as they say, I'm going to have to decide
我是跟注还是扣牌了
whether I'm in or I'm out.
我以为你是爱切特的
I thought you loved Chet.
我的确爱他  亲爱的  但是我...
Oh, I do love him, darling. I really do. I j--I...
知道吗  对我来说...
Well, you know, it's just that for me, it's, uh--
激情不再了
The thrill is gone.
正是
Yes,
已经不再好久好久了
and it's been gone for quite a while.
不过这大钻戒都是把激情带回来了
Although this little fella did bring it back
维持了10分钟
for about ten minutes.
如果他不是你的挚爱  我想
If he's not the one, then I guess you
你不应该嫁给他
shouldn't marry him.
以前这种情况她都嫁了
That's never stopped her before.
再说我们都很想念你
And we miss having you here all the time.
是吧  老爸
Don't we, dad?
-老爸  -儿子
- Dad?  -Dad?
幸亏手机铃响了
Saved by the bell.
是贝克特  我是卡塞尔
Ah, it's Beckett. Castle.
我没听错吧
Hey, did I hear you right?
被害人是薇薇安·马查德  那个灵媒
Our victim is Vivien Marchand, the psychic medium?
你听说过
You've heard of her?
当然  她在曼哈顿某些圈子里很出名的
Yeah. She was very popular in certain Manhattan circles.
事实上  8年前在一个社交派对上
Huh. Matter of fact, she did a reading for me
给我算过一卦
at a society party about eight years ago.
相当邪乎
It was pretty extraordinary.
"邪乎"
"Extraordinary"?
每件事都被她说对了
She got everything right.
知道吗  回想起来
You know what? Come to think of it,
她告诉我一位美丽的女士
she told me that a beautiful woman
会住进我的公寓  住进来就不走了
would one day move into my loft and stay with me forever.
她没说那女的是我母亲
She neglected to mention it was my mother.
她怎么死的
How did she die?
被人用冰锥刺中后颈
Stabbed in the back of the neck with an ice pick,
之后被塞进沙发
and then stuffed into the sofa.
这么说她没预料到这件事
So she didn't see that coming.
死亡时间呢
When did she die?
尸体完全僵硬  我推断大致死亡时间
She's in full rigor. I'd say yesterday afternoon
是昨天下午
is the approximate time of death.
有个维修工说他看到
I got a maintenance worker said
一位男子在下午2点半左右
he saw a man leaving the back door
从后门离开薇薇安的办公室
of Vivien's office around 2:30 yesterday afternoon.
-看到长相了吗  -高个白人  长相凶悍
- Description? - Tall, caucasian and tough looking.
莱恩去查查薇薇安的日程表
All right, Ryan, check Vivien's calendar,
我们看看她昨天的客户
and let's interview her clients from yesterday.
也许凶手就在其中
Maybe one of them saw the guy.
我没搞明白  为什么把她塞进沙发
What I don't get is, why put her in the couch?
被塞进去的时候  她还活着
She was alive when she went in.
脸上的刮痕表明
These scratches on her face
她试图想要爬出来
indicate that she tried to move.
我把她带回解剖室
I'm gonna get her back the lab.
昨天下午3点  她日程表上有个标记
She's got a notation here for 3:00 p.m. Yesterday.
上面写的是TJ
It just says "T.J."
没别的了
And nothing else?
没了  也许TJ是个拜访她的鬼魂
Nope. Maybe T.J. Was a ghost coming to visit.
灵媒不都能看到鬼魂这类的吗
Mediums are the ones that can see ghosts,
-是吧  卡塞尔  -是的  通灵的人能预见未来
- right, castle? - Yes, psychics can tell the future.
灵媒能预知未来也能与灵魂对话
Mediums can tell the future and talk to the dead.
说得好像把通灵师比作骗子
That's like saying that psychics are con artists,
灵媒就是骗子外加大话王
and mediums are con artists and charlatans.
说到底  他们都是假把式
I mean, in the end, they're all just fakes.
说得好像你很明白的样子
You sound pretty certain of yourself.
那是因为我开始做警察的时候
That's because when I started as a cop,
浪费了太多时间追查通天眼的人提供的线报
I wasted a lot of time on clairvoyants calling tip lines
到头来没一个是有价值的线索
with information that never led to anything.
我没想到你这么容易上当
I mean, I'm surprised you're so gullible.
我又没说我能和灵魂交谈
I'm not saying I can speak with the dead.
我也是说我相信世界上有些人
I'm just willing to admit that there are people in this world
比我有更强的感知力
who are more sensitive than me.
这个我信[sensitve有感知力和体贴两个意思]
Now that's not hard to believe.
我自取其辱了  是吧
Walked right into that one.
马查德小姐  你知道有什么人
Ms. Marchand, do you know of anyone
有可能想要伤害你的母亲吗
that might have wanted to harm your mother?
她是一个灵魂纯粹的人
She was a very spiritual person.
她没有什么敌人
She didn't have any enemies.
有证人看到一个高大  头发深色的男子
A witness saw a tall, dark-haired man
昨天2点半从这离开
leaving here around 2:30 yesterday.
听起来像是你母亲认识的人吗
Does that sound like anyone your mother knows?
你上次和她说话是什么时候
When was the last time you two talked?
大概1点钟
Around 1:00.
她说她与今天最后一个客户见过面
She said she had her last client of the day,
她说今天下午
And then she was gonna spend
她想用来冥想
the afternoon in meditation.
知道客户的名字吗
Do you know the client's name?
不知道  是一对母女
No. It was a mother and a daughter.
她们的名字应该在她的记事薄上
Their names should be in her book.
她日程表上有了标示
Well, there was a notation in her calendar
时间是3点  缩写TJ
at 3:00-- the initials "T.J."
知道代表什么吗
Does that mean anything to you?
不知道  抱歉我没帮上忙
No. I'm sorry I can't be more helpful.
我记得这个案子
Hey, I remember this case.
一个男人的妻子失踪了
A guy's wife goes missing,
他显得心急如焚
he seems genuinely distraught,
之后警察发现他有个女友
and then the cops find out he had a girlfriend
-而且他的婚姻也出了问题  -是啊
- and that his marriage was on the rocks. - Yeah.
你母亲参与这个案子了
Did your mother help on that case?
是啊  她感到一个影像  看到他在一个酒吧
Yeah, she had a vision of him at a local bar
和一位漂亮的金发女郎安博尔在一起
with this pretty blonde named Amber,
所以她把这个消息告诉了警察
So she went to the police with the information.
自那时起  他们就把他当做嫌疑犯了
that's when they started looking at him as a suspect.
-之后发生了什么  -他进了监狱
- And then what happened? - He went to prison.
那个案子让我妈妈名声大振
That case really put my mom on the map.
你妈妈有没有
Did your mother continue
继续给警察提供线索
offering the police help after that?
有啊  全国各处提供
Yes, all over the country.
在这过去的十年  我妈妈至少帮助警察
My mother helped put away over a dozen people
将12名罪犯绳之以法
in the last ten years.
这就是佩妮·马查德声称她妈妈帮忙
So here's the list of all the people that Penny Marchand
最后定罪的犯人名单
claims her mom helped to convict.
看看有没有人从监狱出来了
Let's see if any of them are out of jail
-而且还怀恨在心  -好的
- and still holding a grudge. - On it.
薇薇安1点钟的客户来了
Vivien's 1:00 Monday clients are here.
她们声称看清楚了
They say they got a good look
在她办公室那个深色头发的男人的长相
at the dark-haired guy who was in her office.
姓卡西利亚斯  名字分别是宝拉和玛丽娜
Names are Paula and Marina Casillas.
卡西利亚斯  好名字
"Casillas"? That's a good name.
不过很难用复数的所有格形式
Hard to possessive pluralize, though.
卡西利亚斯一家的车坏了
The Casillases' car has broken down,
所以他们出席交响音乐会迟到了
so they will be late for the symphony.
卡西利亚斯一家
The Casillas--s-- Casillases-es...
她们在休息室等你们
They're waiting for you in the lounge.
好的  谢谢
All right. Thanks.
通常情况下  我们都是她周一最后一个客户
Usually, we're her last clients on Monday,
但是我们离开的时候
but when we left,
有个男人在等薇薇安
there was a man there waiting for Vivien.
她见到他很惊讶
She seemed surprised to see him,
好像是他贸然来访
like he wasn't expected.
他看起来很沮丧  看的出来
Oh, and he seemed upset. I could tell.
你能描述一下他的长相吗
Could you describe him?
穿着深色衣服
He was wearing dark clothes.
黑色头发  太阳穴附近头发是灰色的
He had black hair, going gray at the temples.
他脸上还有个疤
Oh, and he had a scar on his face.
我记得她叫他阿尔弗雷德
I think she called him Alfred.
或是艾伯特
Or was it albert?
好的  感谢你们两位提供有价值线索
Okay. Well, thank you, both. You've been very helpful.
你们与薇薇安见面多长时间了
How long had you been going to see Vivien?
四个月了
Four months.
我的丈夫埃米利奥四月去世了
My husband Emilio passed away in April.
我们都很想念他
We both miss him so much.
是她帮你们走出阴霾吗
So she was helping you get closure.
是的
Yes.
就在我们第一次见面  薇薇安
Even at our first session, Vivien...
就已经很了解埃米利奥了
already knew so much about my Emilio.
举个例子
Like what?
她知道他是做维他命生产生意的
Well, she knew he made vitamins for a living.
她知道他喜欢吃番红花鸡肉饭
She knew he loved arroz con pollo.
她也知道他是工作狂
She also knew he was a workaholic.
也知道他是在办公室去世的
And that he even died at the office.
薇薇安说她觉得爸爸有重要的事情
Vivien said she thought daddy had something
要告诉我们
very important to tell us.
她本来昨晚要和他灵魂交流的
She was going to commune with his spirit last night.
现在我们无从得知了
Now we'll never know.
你不会相信的
You're not gonna believe this.
薇薇安女儿很确定
Vivien's daughter is pretty sure
艾伯特就是艾伯特·莫雷诺
that "Albert" is Albert Moreno.
"刀锋"艾伯特·莫雷诺
Albert "The blade" Moreno?
斯巴拉诺家族的前任打手
Former muscle for the Spolano crime family.
薇薇安帮助警察把他抓起来了
So Vivien helped put him away.
他是她的客户
He's her client.
薇薇安告诉艾伯特把钱投到一个
Vivien told Albert thatf he invested in
新泽西的房地产交易
a New Jersey real estate deal,
就会得到幸福
true happiness would be his.
一个月后交易失败  他失去了全部财产
The deal fell through a month ago. He lost everything.
太惨了  给这种家伙糟糕的建议
Ouch. You give a guy like that bad advice,
他会把你活活喂鱼的
he'll see to it you are sleeping with the fishes.
或是用冰锥在脖子上狠狠的戳了窟窿
Or you get stabbed in the neck wi an ice pick...
再塞进沙发里
and stuffed in a couch.
翻译：小易  大卫熊  深深  千花
时间轴：零    后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
艾伯特·莫雷诺真是小喽啰住大房子啊
Albert Moreno is sure living large for a low-level mobster.
黑帮赚来的钱又不交税
Well, I guess mob money goes a little farther
只进不出嘛
when you don't pay taxes on it.
但是对艾伯特来说  永不满足啊
And yet, for Albert, not quite far enough.
我是精明地产的劳瑞·卡特
Loreen Carter from Real Smart Real Estate.
这房子就像是托斯卡纳的珠宝
This house is a tuscan jewel,
对于年轻的情侣再合适不过了
and it's perfect for a young couple.
我们来找莫雷诺先生
We're here for Mr. Moreno.
是的  我去见过她
Yes. I went to see her.
三个月前
Three months ago,
薇薇安告诉我
Vivien told me
我应该把钱投到房地产交易
I should invest in some real estate deal.
她知道我金盆洗手了
She knew that I had... quit my day job.
我打算为退休找好出路
I was looking to set myself up for retirement.
她说投资会给你带来
She told you the investment would
真正的幸福
bring you true happiness,
但是你却赔得一无所有
but instead, you lost it all.
我一度
I was...
很沮丧
upset.
之后她取消了我们的最后一次预约
And then she canceled our last appointment
也不回我的电话
and stopped returning my phone calls.
所以你就在昨天2点左右
And then you decided to pay her a visit
登门拜访了她
yesterday around 2:00?
我告诉她  我正要去见我的经纪人
I told her, I'm on my way to meet my broker.
因为付不起贷款
I'm selling my home because
我不得不卖掉房子
I can't pay my mortgage no more.
之后发生了什么  莫雷诺
And then what happened, Mr. Moreno?
你很生气吗
Did you get angry?
你动手了吗
Did things get physical?
没有  但是我的确很生气
No. But I was mad.
当我生气的时候  别人都会很紧张
And when I'm mad, sometimes people get nervous.
她求我让我等待宇宙裁决一切命数
She begged me to let the universe sort itself out,
还说她后面还有一个
and she said she was late
在市中心的预约要迟到了
for an appointment uptown.
她说和谁有约了吗
Did she say with whom?
没有  那时  我见经纪人也要迟到了
No. By then, I was late to meet my broker,
我就走了  时间是2点半左右
So I left, about 2:30.
就这样
And just like that...
宇宙
The universe?
确实自有定夺
It sorted itself out.
抱歉  我没听懂
I'm--I'm sorry. I don't understand.
我发现我经纪人的搭档
Turns out, my, uh, broker's partner
就是劳瑞  我高中时候的女友
is, uh, Loreen here, my high school sweetheart.
我们82年分手
We broke up in '82,
但是我们还没有忘记对方
but we never got over each other.
我再见到她的第一眼起
The minute I laid eyes on her again,
我就没再离开过
I haven't left her side,
我也从未如此快乐
and I never been so happy.
这么说  薇薇安说对了
So... Vivien was right.
投资房地产
Investing in the real estate deal
使你破产
brought you to bankruptcy,
却让你找到了劳瑞
which, in turn, brought you to Loreen
和幸福
and true happiness.
邪乎
Extraordinary.
感觉如何
So what do you think?
我想在宇宙解决事情之前
Well, I think it's possible he might have killed Vivien
他可能已经杀了薇薇安
before the universe righted itself.
不是这个  而是艾伯特和劳瑞
Not about that. About them--Albert and Loreen.
擦肩而过的爱人因命运而重聚
Star-crossed lovers reunited by fate.
你是说纯属巧合而重聚吧
You mean reunited by coincidence.
让我猜猜  你不相信命运
Oh, let me guess. You don't believe in fate.
灵魂伴侣呢
Soul mates?
不信
No.
独角兽  小精灵  双重彩虹呢
Unicorns, fairies, double rainbows?
你有想过你的公仔们会在晚上起来
Didn't you ever think your dolls used to get up at night
-摆弄你的玩具么  -抱歉  没有
- and play with your toys?  - Sorry.
让我猜猜
Mm. Let me guess.
你是那些讨人烦的小孩
You were one of those annoying 6 year olds
6岁时就不相信圣诞老人
who stopped believing in Santa Claus
因为你知道了
because you figured out he couldn't travel
他的速度不可能快过光速
faster than the speed of light.
我三岁就不信了  而且我们家没有烟囱
I was 3, and we didn't have a chimney.
莫雷诺那进展如何
How'd it go with Moreno?
我的直觉不是他
My gut says it's not him.
但我们还得调查他的不在场证明
But we still have to look into his alibi.
虽然你不相信命运
Oh, so you don't believe in fate,
但你的直觉真有魔力
yet your "Gut" Has magical properties.
太酷了  斯嘉丽[《X档案》女主角]
That's cool, Scully.
我们申请了薇薇安大多数有案底的客户资料
We got calls out on most of Vivien's dirty dozen.
明天应该会有报告
We should hear back tomorrow.
同时  我们调查了她的客户档案
Meanwhile, we've been going through her client files--
大厅的来访纪录  网络搜索记录
trips to the hall of records, Internet searches,
还拿到一些验尸报告
even got ahold of some autopsy files.
非常详尽的资料
Pretty intimate stuff, too.
瞧  卡塞尔
You see, Castle?
调查研究  这才是她让人相信
Research--that's how she made people believe
她确有天赋的原因
that she has a gift.
我打赌她甚至八年前参加派对时
And I bet that she even looked into you eight years ago
就调查过你
when she went to that party.
我打赌她也调查了宝拉·卡西利亚斯
And I bet she looked up Paula Casillas as well.
这样她才知道她丈夫埃米利奥
That's how she knew that her husband Emilio
有维他命生意
had a vitamin business.
她也是这样才知道
Is that also how she knew
艾伯特·莫雷诺会在
That Albert Moreno would find
破产后找到真爱吗
true love through bankruptcy?
她那是走运
She got lucky.
也许因为仅凭她一人的力量
Oh. Or maybe it's just that she couldn't get
难于得到所需的一切
everything she needed from her abilities alone
因此需要一些额外的调查
and needed to do a little extra digging.
我虽然文思如泉涌
I have a fantastic imagination,
但我写作时
yet I still do a ton of research
还得进行大量研究
when I write a book.
一堆怀疑主义者
Surrounded by skeptics.
这才叫真正的警察  兄弟
It's called being a cop, bro.
伟大的神灵啊
oh, great and powerful spirits,
告诉我们  奶奶应该跟切特·帕拉本分手吗
Tell us, should gram break up with Chet Palaburn?
这东西肯定坏了
Ugh! This thing must be broken.
好在我不需要神灵告诉我
Well, luckily, I don't need the spirits to tell me
何时分手
when it's time to say good-bye.
再见  我的爱
Good-bye, my love.
如果你太轻率了呢
What if you're being too hasty?
恋情需要经营  对吗
Relationships take work, right?
不对  爱情不是关于经营  相信我
No, no, no, love is not about work. Trust me.
是关于激情  化学感应  浪漫
It's about passion. It's about chemistry, romance.
是关于你的心跳得很快
It's about your heart pounding faster
因为你迫不及待要见她
because you can't wait to see her.
你们能不能回顾一段
Can either of you look back on a relationship
因为激情不再就结束的恋情
that ended because the thrill was gone,
承认也许你太早放弃爱了
and admit that maybe, you gave up on love too soon?
爸  你不是也和前妻复合了么
Dad, you're back with your ex-wife.
不  她是对的  和吉娜一起时
Ooh. No, she's right. Yeah, with gina.
激情早已逝去
The thrill was long, long gone.
现在激情激烈回归
Now... It is back with a vengeance.
当然  随之而来的还有
Of course, it brought along its friends,
高昂的保养费和购物狂
high maintenance and shopaholic.
抱歉  亲爱的  很抱歉
No, I'm sorry, honey. I'm sorry.
但已经结束了
But it's just--it's over.
我知道
I know it.
嘿
hey.
有案底的那帮人调查有何进展吗
Any news on the dirty dozen?
大多数还在坐牢
Oh, most are still in prison,
但我们想这条调查方向
But we're thinking this line of investigation
可能没有太大进展
may not get us anywhere.
为什么
Why not?
我给一些主管的探长打了电话
I called around to a couple of lead detectives,
想查查薇薇安的介入程度
just to check out the level of Vivien's involvement.
他们说从未听说过她
They say, they've never even heard of her.
她夸大了她的介入程度
She exaggerated her involvement in these cases
以此来建立她的名声
in order to build her reputation back up.
也许这些警察不想承认
Or maybe the cops didn't want to admit
他们有灵媒在帮忙
that they had... a psychic actually helping them.
我是说  怎样的警察会愿意承认
I mean, what police detective would willingly acknowledge
她那样的外行竟是破案天才
that a layperson is as talented at solving crimes as she is?
薇薇安·马查德
Vivien Marchand...
不是灵媒
is not a psychic.
我以警徽打赌
I'd bet my badge on it.
等你看了这个再下定论吧
Don't throw those dice until you take a look at this.
纽约重案组探长小组收
"New york homicide division detective squad."
是薇薇安·马查德寄来的
It's from Vivien Marchand.
是的  今早到的
Yeah, it arrived this morning,
邮戳是星期一  她死的那天
postmarked Monday, the day she died.
这是她的信笺抬头
That is her letterhead.
敬启者
"To whom it may concern,
我感觉我的死期即将来临
I feel that my murder is imminent."
尽管我不知道
"And although I have no idea yet
死亡会在何时何地到来
"where or when this event will occur,
但我已预见到自己的死期
"I have had a vision of my death.
在幻觉中  我不能呼吸
"In the vision, I could not breathe.
我看见穿着黑衣的男子  数字7518
"I saw a man dressed in black, the number 7-5-1-8,
我可以听到从远处传来
"and I could hear a furious pounding
一声重击
"from what seemed to be far away.
抱歉我不能更具体些
I'm sorry I cannot be more specific"--
这个灵媒预期了自己的谋杀案啊
The psychic predicted her own murder!
或者是凶手写来想扰乱视线
Or the killer wrote this in order to throw us off.
去查一下  运气好的话可能会有指纹
Run it. Maybe we'll get lucky with the prints.
-你觉得她真的  -不觉得
- Do you think she really-- - No.
我也不觉得
Yeah, me neither.
蕾妮 有何线索
Hey, Lanie. What do we got?
死亡原因是失血及窒息
We've got cause of death-- blood loss and asphyxiation.
我也可以确认死亡时间
And I'm officially putting the time of death
是周一傍晚5点至7点期间
betweem 5:00 and 7:00 p.M. On Monday evening.
那就排除艾伯特·莫雷诺嫌疑  还有呢
So that les out Albert Moreno. What else?
冰锥上没有刮痕
There were no scratches on the ice pick blade.
是全新的
It was brand-new,
可能特地为这次行凶买的
probably bought special just for the occasion.
她的手机在她手上
And her cell phone was in her hand.
她可能在死前试图打电话求救
She may have tried to dial for help before she expired.
数字和她女儿的
The digits match the beginning
电话号开头吻合
of her daughter's phone number.
1-718-55-
1-718-55--
7-1-8-5
7-1-8-5?
那是信上的数字
Those are the numbers from the letter.
顺序不同
They're in a different order,
但数字一样
but those arthe same numbers.
继续啊  继续说巧合啊
Oh, go on. Go on. Say "Coincidence."
巧合
Coincidence.
我只是说  这根本无懈可击  仅此而已
I'm just saying, it's irrefutable, that's all.
这才不是无懈可击  卡塞尔
It is not irrefutable, Castle.
事实上  这完全就是不攻自破
As a matter of fact, it is completely refutable.
好  继续  攻破我啊
Okay, go on. Refute me.
好吧  听好了
Okay, how about this?
薇薇安在拨打她女儿的电话
Vivien is dialing her daughter's number.
凶手进来  刺中她的脖子
Our killer comes in, stabs her in the neck,
捡起手机
picks up the phone,
扔进沙发里
drops it into the sofa after her,
接着把数字写在信上
and then puts the numbers into the letter
和其他虚假预兆放在一起
along with the rest of the fake predictions.
驳倒
Refuted.
没人在手机里按号码了
No one types a number into a cell phone anymore.
信件的检测结果没有太多线索
Preliminaries on the letter aren't giving us much.
没有可用的指纹和DNA
There are no usable prints and no D.N.A.
薇薇安楼下的邮箱
And the pick up at the mail drop
收信时间是下午6点
in Vivien's building is 6:00 p.m.
时间足够让凶手在她死后
Time enough for the killer to have written it
写下来再寄出去
and mailed it after she was dead.
但是为什么  为什么要这样麻烦呢
But why? Why go through all that trouble?
让我们纠缠杜撰疯狂的理论
To keep us spinning wild theories
追查什么黑衣男子
and chasing after men dressed in black
而不是去调查那些真凭实据
instead of following hard evidence.
你看啊  卡塞尔  这封信甚至没有署名
I mean, come on, Castle. The letter's not even signed.
事实上  我和佩妮·马查德谈了这个
Actually, I talked to Penny Marchand about that.
她说她母亲有可能
She says it's possible her mother
打了一封信但是不署名
would type a letter and not sign it
因为她怕她的预言是错的
in case her prediction was wrong.
她不想别人在网上
She wouldn't want anybody selling
风传她的失准
her mistakes on the internet.
但我们还是不能证明
But we still can't prove
薇薇安真的写了这封信
that Vivien actually wrote the letter.
直到其他预言实现为止
Until her other predictions come true.
我只是
You know, I'm just...
太好了  你回来了  我有些线索
Good. You're back. I think I got something.
还记得薇薇安的第一个大案子吗
Remember Vivien's first big case?
记得  那家伙有失踪的妻子
Yeah, the guy with the missing wife
和金发女友安博尔
and the blonde girlfriend named Amber.
他叫史蒂夫·亚当斯
His name is Steve Adams.
警员正带他过来
Unis are bringing him up right now.
他们从未找到他妻子的尸体
They never found his wife's body.
他因二级谋杀被判七年有期徒刑
He did seven years for second degree.
他两个月前获得假释
They released him two months ago on parole,
仅在他同意佩戴
only after he agreed to wear
追踪器后获得假释
an anklet with a tracking device.
我打给他的假释官  他发过来这个
So I called his P.O., and he sent over this.
追踪系统显示史蒂夫周一下午
The GPS readout puts Steve at Vivien's address
出现在薇薇安家
Monday afternoon.
薇薇安两点结束和宝拉和玛丽娜·卡西利亚斯的会谈
So Vivien finishes with Paula and Marina Casillas at 2:00,
艾伯特·莫雷诺两点半从后门离开
Albert Moreno exists out the back door at 2:30,
三点是她和T.J.的预约
and now it's time for her 3:00 P.M. With T.J.
史蒂夫·亚当斯1:36至2:48期间在那里
Steve Adams was there from 1:36 to 2:48,
等待时机
waiting for his opportunity.
所以他等到她独自一人时
So he waits there until she's alone,
抓住她  刺死她然后塞进沙发里
jus her, stabs her, and then stuffs her in the couch.
-这是骚扰  -放轻松点
- This is harassment!  - Take it easy.
我没有干坏事
I haven't done anything wrong!
就在这里  安静
right through here. Calm down.
他穿着黑色衣服
Ah. He's wearing all black.
这肯定是巧合
It's gotta be a coincidence.
或者黑色是一种罪
Or black is the new guilty.
我没杀她
I didn't kill her.
你是最后一个看见她的人
You were the last one to see her alive.
你踝环上追踪器显示
The gps on your anklet indicates
你在薇薇安被杀当天
that you were at Vivien's office
在她的办公室待了超过一小时
For over an hour the day that she was killed.
没错  但不是你想的那样
Yeah, but it's not what you think.
上周  我接到叫科迪·多内力打来的电话
Last week, I got a call from a guy named Cody Donnelly.
他是真人秀节目制作人
He's a reality TV producer.
他说他可以帮我洗脱罪名
He said he could help me clear my name.
那他打算怎么做
How was he gonna do that?
在我妻子失踪的第二天
The day after my wife disappeared,
薇薇安·马查德告诉警察她在幻影中
Vivien Marchand told the cop she did a vision at the bar
看见我和女友安博尔在酒吧
with my girlfriend Amber.
这是真的
Which was true.
我当时在那里吗  是的
That I was there? Yeah.
但她开始说还看见其他幻影
But then she started saying she had other visions--
我杀我妻子  这个我没有
Visions that I murdered my wife, which I did not do--
但关于安博尔  她对了一次
bue was right once, about Amber,
结果大家都相信她
so everyone believed her.
但薇薇安也撒谎了
Only Vivien had lied about that, too.
你的意思是
What do you mean?
科迪·多内力告诉我他有
Cody Donnelly told me he had proof that Vivien
证据可以证明
was a customer in the same bar
薇薇安那天也去过那间酒吧
where I took Amber that day.
是她亲眼看到我
So she saw me, all right, with her own eyes.
根本就没有灵媒这回事  没有
There was nothing psychic about it, nothing.
所以你想到  假如可以证明薇薇安是个骗子
So you figured if you could prove that Vivien was a fraud,
那么也许人们也会相信
that maybe people would believe
你没有杀害你妻子
that you hadn't killed your wife as well.
我是无辜的  但多亏了薇薇安
I'm an innocent man, but thanks to Vivien,
全国人民都相信我杀了我妻子
everyone in the state believed that I killed my wife.
她需要预约
She got a book deal.
我预约了7点至10点
I got 7 to 10.
那科迪·多内力的目的是什么
And what was in it for Cody Donnelly?
他想让我和薇薇安出现在他的真人秀里
He wanted me and Vivien to be in his reality show,
《你毁了我的人生》
"You've ruined my life."
我喜欢那节目
Oh, I love that show.
这是冤假错案的人们对那些错判官
I-it's where people unleash their righteous fury
发泄正义怒火的地方
against those who have wronged them.
结局通常是一笑泯恩仇
Usually ends in tears and a hug.
科迪和我带上摄影队去了她办公室
Cody and me, we went to her office with a camera crew.
我们坐在车上等了将近一小时
We sat outside in the van for almost an hour.
当她最终出现时  我质问她
When she finally came out, I confronted her.
我骂她是骗子
I called her fake.
科迪让我搞大这事  我照做了
Cody told me to make it big, so I did.
那薇薇安有何应对
And what did Vivien do?
她害怕了
Mostly she freaked.
接着她上了一辆出租车跑了
Then she got in a cab and took off.
科迪马上载我回公寓  在45大街
Cody dropped me at my apartment on second and 45th,
我再也没见到她
and I never saw her again.
全球卫星定位系统表明
Gps puts Adams at his apartment
薇薇安被杀时  亚当斯在自己公寓里
at the time that Vivien was murdered.
寻找目击证人核实这事
Find me some witnesses that can verify that.
你不相信全球卫星定位系统
You don't trust the gps?
不信  这东西可以篡改
No, those things can be tampered with.
薇薇安告诉她女儿
So Vivien told her daughter
她整个下午都在办公室
that she was gonna be at the office all afternoon,
而在2:45时  她上了一辆出租车离开
and then at 2:45, she takes a cab and leaves
去见T.J.  姓名不详
to see T.J., whoever that is.
去找史蒂夫·亚当斯的制作人科迪·多内力
Let's get ahold of Steve Adams' producer, Cody Donnelly.
我想早上见见他
I want to see him and his footage of Vivien
和关于薇薇安的脚本
first thing in the morning.
收到
You got it.
很高兴你回来了
I am so glad that you are home.
我今天衰到令人难以置信
You would not believe the day I had.
你就别和我比了
Oh, I think I got you beat.
妈妈  怎么了
Mother, what's wrong?
你为何还和切特叔叔订婚呢
And why are you still engaged to uncle Chet?
哦  理查德
Oh, Richard.
切特死了
Chet is dead.
什么
What?
怎么回事
How?
我今早去他家里
I went to his apartment this morning,
他孩子在那里
and his kids are there-- boomer and lotte.
他们说
They said...
他在睡梦中中风了
He'd had a stroke in his sleep.
神哪  我简直
I mean, god, I...
他还那么年轻  而且
He was so young, and...
妈妈  我很抱歉
Mother, I am so sorry.
然后
So...
博莫和洛蒂看到了这戒指
Boomer and Lotte see the ring.
就以为他们的老爸
Naturally they assume that their father
和我已经订婚了
and I are engaged,
他们很担心
and now they're worried
我会如何面对这个噩耗
about how I'll handle the news.
然后
And, uh,
我陪了他们一天
I spent the whole day with them,
帮着接待客人
receiving visitors.
他们不停跟我讲
And they kept telling me...
自从和我在一起后
How happy their father had been
他们的父亲是多么的快乐
since we'd been together,
他是如何的
and how I was...
爱我
the love of his life.
而我却准备要  拒绝他
And there I was, about to break his heart.
他们还要我做追悼致辞
And now they want me to give the eulogy.
我怎么做得到
I don't think I can.
哦  理查德
Oh, Richard.
-妈妈 太遗憾了   -我知道
- Mom, I'm sorry.   - I know.
-别伤心了  -只是
- I'm sorry.  - It's just so...
去  快去  她在那儿
Go, go, go, go. There she is.
好  我看到她了  快去拦住她
All right. I see her. Go get her.
薇薇安·马查德  还记得我吗
Vivien Marchand. You remember me?
你跟条子说"看"到我在酒吧
You told the cops that you had a vision of me in a bar.
这是从科迪·多内力那儿拿到的胶片吗
Is that the footage from Cody Donnelly?
是啊  他在审讯室等你
Yep. He's waiting for you in interrogation.
卡塞尔呢
Where's Castle?
他有些私事要处理
Oh, he had some personal issues he had to deal with.
情况怎样
What do we got?
目前  就和史蒂夫·亚当斯说的一样
So far, it's going just like Steve Adams says.
薇薇安从办公室出来  他直接冲了上去
Vivien comes out, he gets in her face.
-我可以证明  -快把他弄走
- And I can prove it...  - Get him outta here...
她上了计程车
She gets in the cab.
看到一部分车牌号了
And we get a partial on the license plate.
我去查一下  看能否查出
I'll run it down. See if I can find out
-她在哪儿下的车  -关掉  快关掉
- where the taxi dropped her off.  - Turn it off. Turn it off.
贝克特警探
Detective Beckett.
你好  佩妮  有什么事吗
Hi, Penny. What are you doing here?
我们可以单独谈谈吗
Is there somewhere we could talk privately?
怎么了  是想起什么了吗
What's wrong? Did you remember something?
不
No.
不是关于那个
It's not that.
我想说
I'm afraid I wasn't
我之前没有完全说出事实
completely honest with you the other day.
事实上
The fact is,
我和我妈妈一样也有一点超能力
I have a little bit of what my mother did.
有时候我会做些很灵验的梦
Sometimes I have dreams that are meaningful.
昨晚  我梦到了你
Last night, I had a dream about you.
然后呢
Okay.
我也说不清  就是强烈的感觉到
And I can't really explain why, but I feel very strongly
我必须告诉你些事情
that I'm supposed to tell you something,
是很重要的事  你准备好了吗
something important. Are you ready?
好了
I'm ready.
-亚历山大  -什么亚历山大
-  Alexander.  - Alexander?
亚历山大  我不知道他是谁或对你有何意义
Alexander. I don't know who he is or what he means to you.
我不认识叫亚历山大的人
I don't know any Alexander.
你会的  你会遇见一个叫亚历山大的人
You will. You will meet an Alexander.
对你来说他将是个极其重要的人
And he will be extremely important to you.
在未来的某一天  他会救你的命
At some future date, he may save your life.
好吧
Okay.
知道这个消息太高兴了
Um, good to know.
谢谢你警探
Thank you, detective.
我才要谢谢你呢  佩妮
Thank you, Penny.
眼见为实  老兄
Candid reality gold, mate.
在我看来  是著名的神秘小说写手
Cody Donnelly presents-- famous mystery writer
为了"做调查"而跟着一个彪悍而又漂亮的
follows a tough but beautiful New York cop around
纽约条子
"For research."
她不会同意的  她是个不折不扣的
Ah, she'd never go for it. She's a real b--
多内力先生  感谢你能过来
Mr. Donnelly, I appreciate you coming...
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
我再插一句  我想说的是"教条维护者"
Uh, for the record, I was gonna say "Big rule follower."
我对天发誓  绝对不是在讨论案子
I was not discussing the case. I swear to god.
《赤裸热浪》明天就发售了
Uh, "Naked Heat" comes out tomorrow,
科迪呢  正在赞赏广告牌
and Cody here was admiring the billboards.
海报上惹火的照片是你吗
Is that your smoking-hot silhouette on the posters then?
不是
No.
多内力先生  离开了薇薇安的办公室后
So, Mr. Donnelly, where did you go
你去了哪儿
after you left Vivien's office?
录完那段节目
After we got all that great footage,
我把史蒂夫送回了家
I dropped Steve off at his place
那时候大约是  三点半左右
around, uh, well, 3:30 or so.
接着就接到了薇薇安·马查德的电话
That was just before Vivien Marchand called me.
是吗  她想做什么呢
Really? And what did she want?
挽救她的事业
To save what was left of her career.
她清楚我们录的视频对她很不利
I mean, she knew the film I had on her was damaging.
她说若我毁了胶卷  她会给我更好的东西
She said if I buried it, she'd give me something better.
什么更好的东西
Better like what?
比如谋杀案
Better like murder.
薇薇安说她在追踪一个杀人犯
You see, Vivien said she was hot on a killer.
而且比史蒂夫·亚当斯那次更加轰动
She said it was bigger than Steve Adams.
这次  会出现尸体
This time, there was a body.
她让我拍下她揭露罪犯的
She was gonna let me film the moment that she confronted
那一刻
the soon-to-be accused.
她说她还得证实最后一个疑点
She said that she had to confirm one last suspicion,
而我必须准备好  随时待命
and that I had to be ready to go at a moment's notice
因为我们要抓一个杀人犯
'cause we were gonna catch a killer.
什么时候揭露呢
And when was this confrontation gonna take place?
很快  两小时后我收到一条紧急短信
Straightaway. I got an urgent text about two hours later.
我召集了工作人员  包括保安
I-I gathered up my crew, including security,
以为可以大干一场了
thinking this was it.
结果我给她打过去时  没人接听
And then when I called her back, no answer.
我猜那时她已经死了
I'm guessing she was already dead.
有关于薇薇安追踪谋杀案的消息吗
Any news on Vivien's hunt for a murderer?
确实有人来找她解决
Well, she had several clients who came to her
一些家族疑案
because of unsolved crimes in the family,
但我们和那些人谈过
but the ones that we talked to
他们说那些案子和
said that their cases are just as cold now
之前一样毫无进展
as when they first came to her.
嘿  我找到了那辆计程车
Hey, I found the cab.
司机说他把薇薇安带到了
The driver says he took Vivien to a residence
112大道沿河边的居民楼
at 112th and riverside.
看门人说记得薇薇安
The doorman says he remembers Vivien
上楼到2C号房间
going up to apartment 2c.
租住人是尼克和托尼·约翰斯顿
It's rented to Nick and Toni Johnston.
-托尼·约翰斯顿  -T.J
- Toni Johnston.  - T.J.
若薇薇安在死的那天来见托尼·约翰斯顿
If Vivien came to see Toni Johnston the day she died,
肯定是有很重要的事
it had to have been about something important,
比如和她追踪的杀人犯有关
like this killer she was chasing.
不过你可能会说那只是巧合
But you'll probably say it was just a coincidence.
卡塞尔  我相不相信命运女神
Castle, why is it so important to you
灵媒或圣诞老人
that I believe all this stuff about
对你来说就这么重要吗
Fates and psychics and Santa Claus?
因为
Because...
若你不相信可能存在魔力
If you don't believe in even the possibility of magic,
你就永远不会发现它
you'll never, ever find it.
-请问有事吗  -托尼吗
- Can I help you?  - Toni?
我是凯特·贝克特警探
I'm detective Kate Beckett,
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
and this is Richard Castle.
哦  天哪  天哪  天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
我担心死了
I'm so stressed out.
这简直太诡异了
I can't believe this is happening.
看来你知道薇薇安被杀害一事了
So you know that Vivien was murdered?
我昨天看到新闻报道后
When I saw the paper yesterday,
差点把燕麦片给吐了出来
I nearly puked up my oatmeal.
周一薇薇安为什么会来你家
Why did Vivien come to visit you on Monday?
那可是件涉及隐私的事
This is all very personal and private,
而且事关我的性生活
and it involves my sex life.
你能保证不说出去吗
Will you promise to keep it confident?
放一百个心
Absolutely.
好吧  今年年初  我做了件很糟糕的事
Okay, earlier this year, I did a terrible thing.
我和我老公的上司有过一段婚外情
I had an affair with my husband's boss.
我们非常谨慎  没被人发现
Very discreet-- no one ever knew about it.
所以薇薇安才跟我联系
That's why Vivien called me.
她知道那件事
She knew about the affair?
她突然给我打电话
She called me out of the blue.
她知道我们是在公司的圣诞晚宴上相遇的
She knew we met at the company Christmas party,
经常在星爆旅馆私会
that we used to rendezvous at the Starburst hotel,
以及其他所有事情
everything.
邪乎啊
Extraordinary.
我也这样想
I know, right?
我脑子里一团乱
I mean, my mind was totally blown.
婚外情
An affair?
约翰斯顿太太  薇薇安有没有
Mrs. Johnston, did Vivien ever
跟你提过有关谋杀案的事
talk to you about mumder?
没有  她只说她知道
No. She just told me she knew
我如何让我老公尼克戴了绿帽子
how I had cheated on Nick, my husband,
还问了很多关于他的问题
and then she asked me a lot of questions about him.
什么样的问题
What kind of questions?
他是否脾气很暴躁  我是否感到安全
She asked if he had a temper, and if I felt safe.
她确定尼克知道我出轨的事
She was sure Nick did know about the affair.
薇薇安说伴侣一般都知道的
Vivien said the spouse always knows.
她有没说过是怎么知道这些
Did she ever say how she knew all of this,
如此私密的事情的呢
all of this incredibly personal information,
这些细节根本不可能会有记录
the details of which could not be readily found
也不能从网上获得
at a hall of records or through an internet search?
她说了
Oh, yeah.
就是我外遇的那个人
The guy I was cheating with?
他一点不漏的告诉了她
He told her everything.
那我得跟他谈谈
You know, I'm gonna have to speak with him.
哦  不行  你不可能和他谈了
Oh, oh, you can't. I mean, you can't.
他已经死了  所以我才没再见过他
He's dead. That's why we stopped seeing each other.
他四月份死的  心脏病
He died last April. Heart attack.
你是说你死去的情人
You're telling me that your dead lover
跟薇薇安讲了你们的婚外情
told Vivien about your affair?
没错
That's right.
她说埃米利奥来到了她的梦中
She said Emilio came to her in a dream.
埃米利奥
Emilio?
埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯
Emilio Casillas.
你的情人是埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯
Your lover was Emilio Casillas?
怎么样
Well?
埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯的尸检报告
Emilio Casillas' autopsy file
可是相当有趣啊
makes for some very interesting reading.
先说你觉得他有可能是被谋杀的吗
But do you think he was murdered?
根据法医的记录  除了严重心力衰竭这一
According to the M.E.'s notes, in addition to
致死病症外
the cause of death, which was massive heart failure...
卡西利亚斯还有脱发的症状
Casillas showed signs of alopecia,
他的指甲也在变薄
and his fingernails were thinning.
那到底说明了什么呢
Which means what, exactly?
我得挖出尸体做些检查
I'd have to exhume the body and run some tests,
不过有可能是硒过量引起的
but it could be toxic overdose of selenium.
什么是硒
And what's selenium?
那是人身体里面含有的一种矿物质
It's a mineral that's naturally found in the body,
少量的硒对人是有好处的
and in small amounts, is good for you.
有人甚至把它放入减肥药和健康饮品里
They even sometimes add it to diet pills, health drinks.
但过量的话就会引起中毒
But too much of it can be poisonous.
健康饮品
Health drinks.
可能卡西利亚斯的公司产的维他命药片里
Maybe it was also in the vitamins
也有那种东西
that the Casillases made.
也就是说工厂里可能有
So that would mean it would be at the factory.
薇薇安告诉托尼  她老公知道
Vivien told Toni that her husband knew
她和埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯的事
about the affair with Emilio Casillas.
而托尼的老公尼克在卡西利亚斯的公司上班
So Toni's husband Nick works at the Casillases' company.
他能轻易拿到硒并接近埃米利奥
He would have easy access to the selenium and to Emilio.
卡西利亚斯的女儿不是说了吗
And didn't the Casillases' daughter
她父亲死于办公室
say that her father died in the office?
他可能就是在那儿被毒死的
That's probably where he received the fatal dose.
也即尼克·约翰斯顿
So Nick Johnston
发现了他老婆和他上司有一腿
figures out his wife is sleeping with his boss...
就毒死了他
And he poisons him.
然后尼克发现薇薇安在追查他
And then Nick discovers that Vivien's on to him,
就把她也杀了
and kills her, too.
嘿  我刚和尼克·约翰斯顿的工头谈过
Hey. So I just spoke to, uh, Nick Johnston's foreman.
他说薇薇安死的那天
He said that Nick clocked out early
尼克5点就走了
the day that Vivien died, at 5:00.
但他妻子说他至少到了7点才回家
But his wife said he didn't get home till at least 7:00.
那他就有足够的时间
Well, that would've been plenty of time for him
在信件被收走前赶到薇薇安的办公室
to get to Vivien's office, murder her, write the letter,
杀了她  并写好信
all before the mail was picked up.
但他又是怎么发现薇薇安找过托尼的呢
But how did he find out that Vivien talked to Toni?
-托尼不可能告诉他啊  -托尼是没有
- Toni wouldn't have told him.  - Oh, Toni didn't.
但薇薇安说了
But Vivien did.
工头说有个女人来找过尼克后
The foreman said that Nick asked for the time off
他就请假了
after he was visited by a woman,
那个女人看起来很像薇薇安·马查德
a woman who looked a lot like Vivien Marchand.
这样看来  薇薇安在按计划行事
So Vivien was putting her plan into action.
他把尼克引诱到办公室来
She'd bring Nick down to her office,
然后打电话给科迪·多内力
then she'd call Cody Donnelly,
让他带拍摄人员过来
have him bring his camera crew.
她将揭穿尼克谋杀
She would confront Nick
埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯的真相
about Emilio Casillas' murder,
并全部拍下来
capture it all on film.
薇薇安打算解决埃米利奥的案子
Vivien was about to solve Emilio's murder,
然后找回以前"纽约最著名灵媒"的
and then be returned to her former glory
光荣称号
as New York's most famous psychic medium.
她可真是大胆啊
It's a pretty bold move.
但她一开始是怎么接触到
But how did she get on to
埃米利奥的案子的呢
Emilio's murder in the first place?
我要说多少遍啊
How many times do I have to say it?
她是个  灵媒
She was a... psychic.
-不好意思  你说什么  -灵媒
- I'm sorry. What?  - Psychic.
或者
Or...
她只是直觉很敏锐罢了
Maybe just very intuitive.
根据薇薇安的记录
According to Vivien's notes,
宝拉说过埃米利奥在死之前的几个月
Paula said Emilio had been working longer hours
工作时间加长了
in the months before his death.
她标记了"外遇?"
She wrote "Affair?"
她还写了这个
She also wrote this.
星爆旅馆
Starburst hotel.
那是离埃米利奥的办公室最近的
That's the closest place to Emilio's office
有大把钟点房
that rents by the hour.
那儿的经理说薇薇安上星期去过
The manager there said Vivien came by last week.
他向她证实了
He confirmed to Vivien
那对情侣自年初起就是常客了
that the lovebirds had been regulars early this year,
她给了他200美元的信息费
and she gave him 200 bucks for his trouble.
好吧  那薇薇安又是怎么从怀疑有外遇
Okay, but how does Vivien go from "Affair" in general
到确定外遇对象是托尼·约翰斯顿的呢
to "Affair with Toni Johnston"?
老兄  这可是一个大突破啊
That, my friends, is a pretty big leap.
没错  确实如此
Yeah, uh, that is
不过你看了这照片就知道了
until you see the picture.
这是从薇薇安的调查资料里找到的
This is from Vivien's research.
穿红色礼服的是托尼  她旁边的是埃米利奥
This is Toni in the red dress, and Emilio next to her,
在上一次公司的圣诞晚会上
At the company's last christmas party.
相当舒适  哈
Pretty cozy, huh?
她是从哪里得到的
Where did she get this?
噢  卡西利亚斯的维他命制造厂里
Oh, there's a bulletin board
有一个告示牌
At the Casillases' vitamin factory
员工会把照片公布在上面
Where employees post pictures.
她可能从那儿拿到的
She could've taken it from there.
薇薇安怀疑埃米利奥有了外遇
So Vivien suspects that Emilio is a cheater.
她拿到了他的验尸报告
She gets ahold of his autopsy file,
开始想他可能是因为外遇被杀的
Starts thinking that maybe his cheating got him killed,
然后她开始做一些循例调查
And she starts doing her usual research
去证明她的想法
To prove her theory.
所有的调查结果都将怀疑
And all of this investigation leads her right back
指向了尼克·约翰斯顿
To Nick Johnston.
她想通了所有的事
She had it all worked out...
直到那个尴尬时刻
Right up until that awkward moment
尼克·约翰斯顿用碎冰锥
Where Nick Johnston stabbed her
刺穿了她的脖子
in the neck with an ice pick
将她扔进沙发
And fed her to the couch.
你们抓错人了  我没有杀那个灵媒
You got the wrong guy. I didn't kill that psychic.
我们知道她找过你
We know she came to see you.
没错  她说要私下跟我谈谈
Yeah, she said she needed to talk to me in private,
说很紧急  有关我的妻子
Said it was urgent, had something to do with my wife,
所以我提前打卡下班
So I punched out early and
去了她住宅区的办公室
went uptown to her office.
那你到了之后做了什么
And what did you do when you got there?
什么都没做  门是锁上的
Nothing. The door was locked.
我敲了十分钟的门  没人开
I pounded on it for ten minutes. Nobody answered.
我以为她放我鸽子  所以就回家了
I figured she was blowing me off, so I went home.
这故事相当合理
That's a pretty convenient story.
这是事实
It's the truth.
好的  不如我们开始聊一下埃米利奥·卡西利亚斯
Okay. Why don't we start talking about Emilio Casillas?
说些什么
What about him?
你知道他跟你妻子有一腿
You knew that he was sleeping with your wife.
他们以为自己很小心
They thought they were being so careful,
但是没错  我知道了
but yeah, I knew.
-你做了什么  -什么都没做
- So what did you do? - Nothing.
别开玩笑  尼克
Seriously, Nick?
你居然期望我相信
Do you actually expect me to believe
你只是坐在一边  让你的老板
That you just sat by and let your boss
从你那抢走你的妻子
Take your wife away from you?
-你认为我有那么笨吗  -她没那么笨
- Do you think I'm that dumb? - She's not that dumb.
我想这不重要了
I guess it doesn't matter now.
我
I...
我发现了以后  我去找埃米利奥
When I found out, I went to Emilio
叫他别再跟我老婆见面
And I asked him to stop seeing her.
-然后怎么了  -他不肯
- and what happened? - He said no.
他跟我老婆是相爱的
He was in love with her.
我威胁要告诉他妻子
I threatened to tell his wife,
但他只是说  做你该做的吧
And he just said, "Do what you gotta do."
我决定我不会替他做这卑劣的事
So I decided that I wasn't gonna do his dirty work for him.
如果他想离开他三十年的妻子
If he wanted to leave his wife of 30 years,
那么他应该像个男人  自己去做
Then he should just be a man and do it himself.
但我想挽救我的婚姻
But I wanted to save my marriage,
所以我对这事绝口不提
So I kept my mouth shut.
两周后  埃米利奥就死了
Two weeks later, Emilio was dead.
而且他的死并不是拜你所赐
And you did nothing to help that along,
你是这个意思吗
Is that what you're saying?
拜我所赐什么啊  他心脏病发作
Help what along? He had a heart attack.
当一个谎话连篇  偷情的混蛋的压力
The stress of being a lying, cheating as shat
终于令他倒下了
Finally did him in.
佩妮·马查德来了  她说这很紧急
Penny Marchand is here. She says it's urgent.
佩妮  什么事
Penny, what is it?
探长  我有很重要的事要告诉你
Detective, I have something important to tell you.
噢  佩妮  这是关于那个神秘男子吗
Oh, Penny, is this about the mystery man?
因为我真的不认识任何亚历山大
Because I really don't know any Alexander.
-亚历山大  -没错  我等一下再告诉你
-Alexander? - Yeah, I'll tell you about it later.
佩妮  我正在调查一个非常重要的
Penny, I'm in the middle of a very important--
探长  你要听我说
Detective, you have to listen to me.
我知道谁杀了我妈妈
I know who murdered my mother.
先让我
So let me just...
搞清楚
Get this straight.
你说你做了一个梦
You're telling me that you had a dream
你妈妈被共济会会员杀了
That your mother was murdered by the freemasons.
在梦里  我们正在共济会的大厅
In the dream, I was having dinner with my mother
吃晚饭
In a masonic hall.
她非常忧虑
She was very concerned.
她不断指着房间里的人
She kept pointing to men around the room
说  问那些共济会会员发生什么事
And saying, "Ask the masons what happened.
这是你唯一能查出真相的方法了
That's the only way you'll get closure."
进度怎么样  史蒂夫·亚当斯的不在场证明核实了
Where are we? Steve Adams alibi checked out.
那尼克·约翰斯顿呢
What about Nick Johnston?
我跟他说不要离开城里
Well, I told him not to take any trips out of town
直到我们把案子解决了
Until we get this sorted out.
好消息是  有了共济会会员这个线索
Well, the good news is, with this freemasons lead,
我们有了一批新的嫌疑人
We have a whole new crop of suspects.
共济会会员
Freemasons?
别理他
ignore him.
那么宝拉和玛丽娜·卡西利亚斯
So Paula and Marina Casillas...
如果他们知道
If they knew
埃米利奥有外遇  那就会是动机
That Emilio was cheating, that would be motive.
或者她们发现
Maybe they found out that
薇薇安正调查他的死
Vivien was investigating his death.
但她们是薇薇安的客户
But they were Vivien's clients.
为什么凶手会向一个灵媒寻求慰藉
Why would murderers go to a psychic for closure?
她们还有薇薇安遇害
They also have an alibi for
那天的不在场证明
the evening Vivien was killed.
制服警员调查了那家
Uniforms canvassed the restaurant
她们跟朋友吃饭的餐馆
Where they were dining with friends.
她们五点到七点都在餐馆
They were there from 5:00 p.M. Till after 7:00.
那家餐馆离薇薇安的办公室近吗
Was this restaurant anywhere near Vivien's office?
是的  就在转角处  新开的  叫共济餐馆
Yeah, around the corner. New place. Uh, mason's.
求诸共济  他们会给你真相
"Ask the masons, and they will give you closure."
别神神叨叨的了
Let's not get carried away.
求诸共济  拜托啦
Ask the masons, please.
就这一次
Just this once.
要相信
believe.
-你知道这发生什么事了吗  -不
- You know what's going on here? - No, not really.
我也是
Me neither.
不管发生什么
No matter what happens,
我们都不会再谈这件事
We will never speak of this again.
你好  这是纽约警局的凯特·贝克特探长
Hello. This is detective Kate Beckett with the NYPD.
我可以跟老板谈谈吗
Could I speak with the owner, please?
哈喽  梅森先生
Hello, mr. Mason?
我有几个问题想问你
I have a couple of questions to ask you.
卡西利亚斯女士  起初去拜访薇薇安·马查德
Mrs. Casillas, whose idea was it to go
是谁的主意
and visit Vivien Marchand in the first place?
我们今天过得很糟
We have had a very long day.
请回答问题
Please answer the question.
这是我的主意
It was my idea.
妈妈觉得这太贵了
Mother thought it cost too much,
但我太想念爸爸了
But I missed daddy so much that
什么方法我都会试
I was willing to try anything.
尤其是当她知道
And when she knew
很多你爸爸的私人资料吗
So many private things about your father?
几乎就像跟他在一起
It was almost like being with him,
像他跟我们一起在房间里
Like he was in the room with us.
薇薇安·马查德遇害的那晚
The night that Vivien Marchand was murdered,
你们两个跟朋友去共济餐馆吃饭
The two of you went to dinner with friends at mason's.
没错  那是新开的
That's right. It's a new place.
我妈妈想去试试
My mother wanted to try it.
侍者证实你们五点到七点半
The waiter confirmed that you were there
都在那儿
from 5:00 until 7:30.
那顿饭怎么样  你们有叫红酒吗
How was your meal? Did you order wine with dinner?
是的
Yes.
不  我是说  他们还没有卖酒执照
No, I mean, they don't have a liquor license yet,
所以要自己带
So you bring your own.
那么是你们自己带了红酒去
So you brought your own bottle of wine with you, then?
不
No.
妈妈特地去
Mother went out to the
烟酒商店里买回来的
liquor store and brought us a bottle.
她去了大概二十分钟
She was gone about 20 minutes.
那是什么时候
And what time was that?
可能是十五分  问这些干什么
15 maybe. What's this all about?
宝拉  我们去了那家贩酒店
Paula, we went to the liquor store.
那酒不是五点十五分的时候买的
You didn't buy that bottle of wine at 5:15.
根据这张收据  你在三点十二分买的
According to this receipt, you bought it at 3:12.
同时你还买了冰锥
And at the same time, you bought an ice pick.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你买了那瓶酒之后
You bought that bottle of wine,
把它放在一边
and then you put it aside,
五点十五分的时候
And then at 5:15,
你离开餐馆
You left the restaurant and
直接去了薇薇安的办公室
went straight to Vivien's office
杀了她
and murdered her.
然后你拿回那瓶酒
Then you went and you retrieved the bottle of wine.
回到餐馆
You returned to the restaurant.
继续跟女儿和朋友一起吃饭
You had dinner with your daughter and your friends.
这太荒唐了  妈妈  告诉他们
that's crazy. Mom, tell them.
她为什么要这样做
Why would she do something like that?
去掩盖另一起谋杀
To cover up another murder.
你的父亲
Your father's.
是你发现埃米利奥在偷情
Did you figure out that Emilio was cheating
还是他告诉你的
Or did he tell you?
他跟我说
He told me...
他遇到一个人
That he had met someone...
说那女人年轻漂亮
That she was young and beautiful...
而我只是残花败柳
And that I was just a boring old lady.
我从工厂拿了些硒
I took some selenium from the factory,
然后  每天早上
And... Every morning,
我都加一点在他的咖啡里
I put a little bit in his coffee.
噢  我的天  妈
Oh, my god. Mom...
你想去见薇薇安的时候
When you wanted to go see Vivien,
我为了令你高兴也去了
I went along to humor you,
但是  她知道了
But... She knew things
她不该知道的事
That she shouldn't have known.
然后当她要说埃米利奥
And then when she told you that Emilio wanted
有重要的事想告诉你
To tell you something important...
她打算在晚上
And she said she was going to spend the evening
和他的灵魂沟通
Communing with his spirit...
在他做了那些事以后
The cheating son of a bitch was gonna tell on me.
那个偷情的混蛋要揭发我
After everything that he had done,
我不能让这发生
I couldn't let that happen.
我必须杀了她而阻止他
I had to kill her to stop him.
妈妈  别说了
Mother, stop talking.
我们需要律师
We want a lawyer.
宝拉·卡西利亚斯的律师来了
Paula Casillas has lawyered up.
他已经开始试着制止她招供了
He's already trying to suppress her confession.
会有用吗
Will that work?
这点我怀疑  但宝拉已经不说话了
You know, I doubt it, but Paula's done talking.
你有问她是谁写了那封信吗
Did you ask her who wrote the letter?
你知道的  我没机会问
You know, I didn't get a chance,
那么我猜这依然是一个谜了
So I guess it'll have to remain a mystery.
呃  实际上并不全是
Uh, actually, not quite.
你记得上一个线索
Do you remember the last clue,
-那个从远处传来的敲门声吗  -嗯
- The sound of knocking from far away? - Mm-hmm.
那应该是尼克·约翰斯顿
That would've been Nick Johnston.
他说他敲了几分钟的门
He said he pounded on that door for quite some time
然后才放弃回家
Before he finally gave up and went away.
薇薇安那时候已经死了
Vivien was already dead.
没错  但宝拉可能还在办公室
Yeah, but Paula could've still been in the office
等着他走
Waiting for him to leave,
她有可能听到敲门声
she would've heard the knocking
就像她看见那个电话
Just like she saw the phone,
看见艾伯特·莫雷诺
just like she saw Albert Moreno,
穿着黑色的衣服
Who was probably dressed in black,
所以她只是把这些写进信里误导我们
So she just put it into the letter to throw us off. Hmm.
但根据你谋杀板上的时间表
Only according to your timeline on the murder board,
尼克五点四十五分到办公室的时候
By the time Nick got to the office at 5:45,
宝拉已经回到餐馆了
Paula was back at the restaurant,
办公室是空的
So the office was empty,
除非  当然了  还有薇薇安
Except, of course, for Vivien.
噢  趁我还没忘记
Oh, before I forget...
佩妮说了亚历山大什么
What did Penny say about Alexander?
噢  没什么
Oh, nothing.
只是些毫无意义的瞎话罢了
Just some silly stuff that didn't really make any sense.
怎么了
Why?
因为我的中间名就是亚历山大
Because my middle name is Alexander.
我以为你的中间名是埃德加
I thought your middle name was Edgar.
又去看过了我网站上的
Been perusing the personal section
个人资料了吧
of the Richard Castle website again, have we?
不  我因为埃德加·爱伦·坡
No, I changed my middle name to Edgar
把中间名改成了埃德加
for Edgar Allan Poe
同时我把姓改成了卡塞尔
back when I changed my last name to Castle.
我本名是理查德·亚历山大·罗杰斯
My given name is Richard Alexander Rodgers.
太巧了  是不
What a coincidence, huh?
我觉得他们待客十分周到
I think that was a lovely service.
如果要我说
And if I may say,
你的演讲是最棒的
Your speech was the best.
噢  谢谢你给我写的稿
Oh, well, thank you for writing it. Pfft.
而且我觉得吧  你别和别人说啊
And I think, you know, between the two of us,
我们成功描述了切特的神髓
We managed to capture the essence of Chet.
是的
Yes.
还有博莫和洛蒂
And Boom and Lotte--
非常 非常感激地要回了戒指
Very, very gracious about taking the ring back
还有所有的  噢
And the whole... Oh.
噢  我的天  我感觉太糟糕了
Oh, god. I feel terrible.
听我说
You know...
你真的不需要感到内疚
You really have nothing to feel guilty about.
噢  理查德  别这样  不
Oh, Richard, please. No, if anything,
如果你告诉了切特
By telling Chet you wanted to
你想和他订婚
think about getting engaged,
你给了他多一天的希望
You gave him one more day of hope.
但现在他知道了
But now he knows.
他就在上面  我觉得
He's up there, I assume,
他什么都知道了
And he knows everything.
他知道把他的真心给了一个肤浅
He knows he gave his heart to a woman who is shallow
有点懦弱  而且
And a little cowardly and...
配不上他的女人
Didn't really deserve him.
-干嘛  -过来这里
- What? - Come here.
-噢  亲爱的  我没有心情  -不不
- Oh, honey. I-I don't have-- - no, go.
现在你可以问切特任何事
Now you can ask Chet anything you want to know.
亲爱的  你会原谅我吗
Darling, do you forgive me?
快看  会
There. "Yes."
现在你知道了吧
Now you know. Oh!
你动的  是  没错
You moved it. Yes, I did.
再让我告诉你些事
And let me tell you something else.
切特又不是傻瓜
Chet was nobody's fool.
他了解你的一切
He knew you, all of you.
而且他爱你
And he loved you.
我相信不管他现在在那里  他仍爱着你
I am sure wherever he is now, he still does.
过来
Come on.
去睡吧
Get some sleep.
好
Okay.
理查德
Richard.
不管我这辈子犯过多少错误
Whatever mistakes I've made in my life,
我养了一个好儿子
I raised a good man.